<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soil on Container Gardening</title>
    <link>https://simpson101.github.io/container-gardening/soil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Soil on Container Gardening</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 07:18:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://simpson101.github.io/container-gardening/soil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fertilizer Options for Container Gardening</title>
      <link>https://simpson101.github.io/container-gardening/soil/fertilizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 07:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://simpson101.github.io/container-gardening/soil/fertilizers/</guid>
      <description>Fertilizer Options for Container Gardening In addition to having the right soil mix, choosing the right fertilizer can have a huge impact of your container garden. Plants in containers rely on you entirely for their nutrients since they can&amp;rsquo;t spread their roots to search for food in the ground. This article breaks down the differences between organic and synthetic fertilizers, introduces slow-release options, and discusses how often you should apply fertilizers to ensure your plants thrive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soil Types for Container Gardening</title>
      <link>https://simpson101.github.io/container-gardening/soil/soil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 07:18:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://simpson101.github.io/container-gardening/soil/soil/</guid>
      <description>Soil Types for Container Gardening Understanding the right type of soil to use is a cornerstone of successful container gardening. The choice between potting mix and garden soil is critical, as each offers different benefits and challenges. Additionally, customizing soil mixes to meet the specific needs of your plants can significantly enhance their health and growth.&#xA;Potting Mix vs. Garden Soil Potting Mix Potting mix is specially formulated for containers. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be lightweight and to ensure good drainage and aeration, which are vital for the health of container-grown plants.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
